在这个视频中, 我们要讲的是常规语言
In this video, we're gonna talk about regular languages which are used to
指定编程语言的词法结构。
specify the lexical structure of programming languages. To briefly review
编程语言的词法结构是一组令牌类。
the lexical structure of a programming language is a set of token classes. And
每一个令牌类都由一些字符串组成, 现在我们需要一种方法
each one of the token classes consists of some set of strings. Now we need a way to
指定哪一组字符串属于每个令牌类和常用工具
specify which set of strings belongs to each token class and the usual tool or
这样做是为了使用常规语言, 在这个视频中, 我们将会像
doing that is to use regular languages. So in this video we're going to present like
常规语言并定义它们是什么然后在接下来的视频中我们会讲到
regular languages and define what they are and then in subsequent videos we're going
查看一些在实际编程语言中使用它们的例子。
to look at some examples using them in actual programming languages. To define
一般的语言, 我们通常使用的是正则表达式。
the regular languages, we generally use something called regular expressions. And
每个正则表达式团队现在都是一个集合, 有两个基本规则
each regular expression team now it's a set. There are two basic regular
表达式, 如果我写单个字符C, 那是一个表达式
expressions. If I write the single character C, that's an expression and what
音符是一种包含一根弦的语言, 也就是单字符C,
at the notes is a language containing one string. Which is the single character C,
好的, 这是一种基本形式对于任何一个字符, 我都能得到一种语言
okay, That's one basic form so for any single character I get a language with a
一个字符串语言, 只有一个字符串, 然后唯一的字符串就是那个字符, 另一个字符串
one string language with just and then the only string is that character. Another
普通语言的基本构建块是正则表达式epsilon
basic building block of regular languages is the regular expression epsilon which is
语言, 它只包含一个字符串, 这一次是空字符串。
the language. That contains again just a single string, this time the empty string.
有一件重要的事情要记住, epsilon不是空的
And, one thing that's important to keep in mind is that epsilon is not the empty
语言, 对吧？所以这并不对应于空字符串和空集
language, okay? So this is not correspond to the empty string and the empty set of
字符串, 它是一种只有一个字符串的语言, 即空字符串。
strings. It is a language that has a single string namely the empty string.
除了两个基本正则表达式之外, 还有三个复合规则
Besides the two base regular expressions, there are three compound regular
表达式, 我们把它们按顺序在这里, 第一个是a+b
expressions and we'll just go through them here in order. The first is a + b which
对应于语言a和b的结合, 所以这就是集合a
corresponds to the union of the languages a and b. So this would be the set a such
A在大A的语言中, 小A在大联盟的语言中,
that a is in the language of big A, little a is in the language of big A union,
小b, b用的是小b的语言所以这是两个集合的结合
little b such that b is in the language of little b so just the union of the two sets
字符串, 连接就像字符串连接, 所以如果我有两种语言,
of strings. Concatenation is like string concatenation. So if I have two languages,
a和b, 或者两个正则表达式, a和b, 然后是a和b的串联
a and b, or two regula r expressions, a and b, then, the concatenation of a and b
等于所有的字符串, 小的a和b的连接
Is equal to all of the strings. Little a concatenate with little b where a is drawn
从语言大A和小b从b语言中提取出来, 所以这个
from the language big A and little b is drawn from the language big B. And so this
是交叉分散操作。从a中选择一个字符串。
is cross sporadic operation. Choose a string from a. Choose a string from
大写B, 然后组合, 把它们和字符串放在一起
capital B and then combine, put them together with the string from a first and
从所有可能的组合字符串中选择字符串这是
choosing strings at all possible ways from all possible combined strings and that's
语言a和b连接在一起最后是一种循环
the language a concatenated with b. And finally there's a kind of looping
听不清, 这是一颗恒星或者叫做克雷恩迭代, 或者
[inaudible]. This is pronounced a star or is called the Kleene iteration and, or the
克林闭包, 一颗恒星等于这个结合, 因为i大于等于0
Kleene closure. And a star is equal to the union. For i greater than = zero of a to
i, a的i次方, 这是什么意思呢？a的i次方等于a
the i, a to the i-th power. What's that mean? Well, a to the i-th power is just a
与自己连接的时间, 这是, 听不清, 注意
to concatenated with itself By times. So this is, [inaudible]. And note that
因为i可以等于0, 这里的一种可能性是a的0, 所以a
because i can be = zero, one of the possibilities here is a to the zero, so a
连接自身零次, 这是什么, 这就是语言
concatenate with itself zero times and what is that, well that's the language
这就是语言中包含的空字符串, 所以空字符串是
epsilon. So that's the language contain the empty string. So the empty string is
总是一个恒星的元素, 总结一下最后几张幻灯片
always an element of a star. To summarize the last couple of slides the regular
在一些字母表上的表达式, 其中最小的表达式包括
expressions over some alphabet sigma. The smallest of that expressions that include
下面, 我们来定义一下, 正则表达式r等于e
the following. So, let's define it so, the regular expression r are equal to epsilon
总是一个正则表达式, 或者, 另一种可能是单一的
is always a regular expression. Or, another possibility is the single
字符c, c是我们字母表中的一个元素, 对吧？这很重要
character c where c is an element of our alphabet, okay? So this is important the
正则表达式定义了一些字母表, 所以我们必须选择一个家庭
regular expressions define with respect to some alphabet. So we have to pick a family
会形成正则表达式的基本情况的字符,
of characters that will form the base cases of the regular expression and here,
你知道吗？我们有一个基本的正则表达式
you know? We have one base regular expression for each character in the
字母表, 然后是复合表达式, 另一种可能性是
alphabet. And then we have the compound expressions. So, another possibility Is
正则表达式是两个正则表达式的结合, 另一个是
that a regular expression is the union of two regular expressions. Another one is
这是两个正则表达式的串联, 最后一个是
that the concatenation of two regular expressions. And the last one is that it
可能是一个常规的扩展的迭代, 所以这5个案例是
could be the iteration of a regular expre ssion. So these five cases are the set of
在给定的字母表上的正则表达式, 这里的语法是用来描述
regular expressions over a given alphabet. Now this syntax here for describing the
有这些竖条的正则表达式以及这些不同的情况
regular expressions with these vertical bars and these different cases on the
右手边的r的递归定义, 如果你没见过
right hand side in this recursive definition of r, If you haven't seen this
之前, 这叫做语法, 这对这堂课来说不重要。
before, this is called the grammar. And that's not important for this lecture.
这不是这个, 这节课是关于什么的但是我们讨论的是语法
It's not what this, this lecture is about but we're talking about grammars when we
开始解析, 接下来我想做一些实际构建的例子
get to parsing. Next I'd like to do a few examples of actually building regular
语言, 写山, 思考他们的意思, 就像我们
languages, writing the mountain and thinking about what they mean. And as we
当我们谈论常规语言的时候, 我们首先要说的是
said, whenever we're talking about a regular language, we first have to say
字母表是什么, 所以, 对于这些例子我们用字母0
what the alphabet is. And so, for these examples let's just use the alphabet zero
第一, 这些是由0串组成的语言
and one. So these are going to be languages which consists of strings of 0s
让我们从一个非常简单的例子开始, 让我们考虑一下语言
and 1s. And let's start with a very simple example. Let's think about the language
一颗恒星和什么语言, 所以, 我们知道恒星的定义。
one star And what language that to note. So, well, we know the definition of star.
如果你们还记得的话, 那就是i大于等于0的集合。
If you remember, that was the union over i greater than = zero of one to the i. Okay.
那等于什么呢？这只是一个, 重复一遍, 这就是
And what is that equal to? Well, that's just one. Repeated i that's what the
连接1到i的意思是, 好的, 它的意思是一个和它自己连接的
concatenation of one to the i means, okay. It means one concatenated with itself i
所以这是空字符串, 这是一个连接
and so this is going to be the empty string. That's one concatenated with
它本身是0, 后面跟着一个接着是11后面跟着一个接一个
itself zero followed by one followed by eleven followed by one concatenated with
它本身是3, 后面跟着一个连4, 后面跟着一个
itself three followed by one concatenated with itself four followed by one
和它自己连接很多次, 好的, 这个, 我们可以看到
concatenated with itself any number of times. Okay, And this, and so we can see
这就等于所有的1 s字符串, 好吗？现在我们来做第二个
that this is just equal to all strings Of 1s, All right? Now let's do a second
举个例子, 我们考虑一下语言1, 加上0和
example let's think about the language one. Plus zero concatenated with the
语言一, 好吗？记住, 连接的工作方式是跨产品的
language one, okay? And remember how concatenation works is across products we
取第一个表达式中的每一个字符串并与其中的每一个字符串相结合
take every string in the first expression and combining with every string in the
第二个表达式, 所以这就等于字符串a被画出来的b
second expression. So this is going to be equal to the strings a b where a is drawn
从1+0和b从1开始, 对吧？这是什么时候
from one + zero and b is drawn from one. All right? And, what can that be when
A可以是1或0 b也可以是1所以实际上是这样的
there's two traces for a. A could be one or zero and b could be one so in fact this
等于集合一, 一, 弦一, 一, 二, 听不清
is equal to the set one, one and the strings one, one, the second [inaudible]
字符串1, 1和0, 好吗？我们再做一个例子
of the strings one, one and one zero. All right? Let's do another examples, slightly
更复杂的, 让我们在这里建立一个在一个联合中有两个迭代的
more complex. Let's build up here to having two iterations in a union so have
0+1, 想想它等于什么但我们已经知道了
zero + one and think of about what's that equal to but we've already know what
一个等于。它等于所有的字符串, 所以通过类比为0
one is equal to. That's equal to all strings of ones and so by analogy zero
必须是所有的0串然后我们取这两个数的结合这是
must be all strings of zeroes then we take the union of those two things so this is
其实很容易写出来, 我们把它们写在这个符号里
actually really easy to write out. Let's write them out in this notation so we have
0的i次方, 因为i又等于0, 好的, 这是零和, 1的
zero to the i, for i again equal to zero, okay. That's zero union with. One to the
i或大于等于0, 这是所有的字符串, 这是一个集合
i or greater than = zero. That's the strings of all one. So there's a set at
这是节点的表达式, 最后一个例子, 我们考虑0+1。
this expression to nodes. And for our last example, let's think about zero + one.
现在, 这个迭代, 好了, 我们把恒星放在了两者的结合上
Now, that iterated. Okay? So, we put the star around the union of the two
单独的字符而不是每个字符上的星星
individual character instead of having the star on each character individually in
取这两个东西的结合, 那么这个表达式等于什么呢？
taking the union of the two things. So what is the, what is this expression equal
我们来研究一下恒星的定义, 我们知道, 这是
to? Well, let's work with the definition of star. So, we know. That this is the
联合除以i大于等于0+1的i次方, 这是什么
union over i greater than or equal to zero of zero + one to the i. And what does that
看起来, 首先, 这是空字符串, 对吧？
look like, well, that looks like first of all, there's the empty string, right? And
这个语言中的另一个字符串是, 抱歉, 是从0+1开始的
then another string in this language is, is. Excuse me, is drawn from zero + one
所以这个, 我不应该说另一个字符串但是另一组字符串是
and so this, I shouldn't say another string but another set of strings is the
语言0+1, 然后0+1与自身连接, 对吧？
language zero + one. And then zero + one concatenated with itself, okay? And in
一般, 是0+1, i乘以它本身, 现在是什么
general, is going to be zero + one concatenated by itself i times. Now what
这意味着, 这意味着每一个位置, 如果我们有一串长度i,
does that mean? That means that every position, if we have a string of length i,
在任何位置我们都可以选择0或1代入, 这适用于任何情况
at every position we could pick a zero or a one to plug in and this works for any
长度字符串, 这对每个长度的字符串都是正确的事实上
length string. This is gonna be true of strings of every length and so in fact
这个语言将会是所有的0和1的字符串, 事实上, 这是什么
this language is just going to be all strings Of 0's and 1's. In fact, what that
意思是, 这是对我们字母表的循环效应, 我们的字母表包括
means is this, is the cycle effect on our alphabet. Our alphabet that consists of
0和1所以这是所有字符串的集合你可以在整个过程中形成
zero and one and so this is the set of all strings that you can form over the entire
字母表, 当你有一个规则的时候会有一个特殊的名字
alphabet, And that has a special name when that happens when you have a regular
表示你可以从字母表中形成的所有字符串的集合,
expression that denotes the set of all strings you can form out of the alphabet,
我们把它写成sigma星, 对吧？所以这意味着所有的字符串
we write that as sigma star, okay? So just meaning that all the strings of the
alphabet整合了很多次我想讲的最后一点
alphabet integrated as many times as you like One last point I wanna make on this
在此之前, 我们有很多方法来写每一种
before we go on here is that there are actually lots of ways to write each of
这些不同的语言, 没有一种独特的方式来写这些, 举个例子,
these different languages. There's not a unique way to write these. So for example,
我们用这个语言, 第二个我们做的, 让我换一下
let's just take this language here. The second one that we did, and let me switch
颜色, 另一种写法, 因为我们知道它的意思
colors. Another alternative way to write this since we know the meaning of it is
这两根弦1 1和1 0, 我可以把它写成1, 1, +1
these two strings one, one and one zero, I could have written it as one, one. + one
0, 这意味着完全一样的东西, 我们用了两个表达式
zero and that would mean exactly the same thing. We used two expressions denote
和一颗恒星的情况完全一样, 我可以把它写成1。+1。
exactly the same set similarly with one star, I could write this as one lt;i>. + one.lt;/i>
因为这不会改变任何东西, 加入单弦也不会改变
And cuz this wouldn't change anything. Adding in the single string one wouldn't
改变任何东西, 因为一个已经包含在其中一个。这可能有点
change anything since one is already included in onelt;i>. This might be kind of
这是一种很傻的方式来写这个集合但它并不重要它有一个意义, 它的意思是
alt;/i> silly way to write that set but it doesn't matter it has a meaning and it means exactly
同样的事情, 再次强调的是有不止一种方法
the same things as onelt;i>. The point again is that there is more than one waylt;/i>
要把相同的集合写下来, 写下来, 你可以写多个正则表达式
to write down the same set to write, to write, you can write multiple regular expressions
表示相同的集合。
that denote the same set.